?Are you ready, kids
准备好了吗，孩子们
:Kids
!Aye, aye, Captain
: 儿童
！是啊是啊，队长
.I can't hear you
.我听不到你说话
:[louder ]
!Aye, aye, Captain
：[大声]
！是啊是啊，队长
♪ ...Oh
♪ ...哦
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
?under the sea ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
?在海底♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Absorbent and yellow
.and porous is he ♪
♪ 吸水性和黄色
.他是多孔的♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ If nautical nonsense be
...something you wish ♪
♪ 如果航海方面的废话是
...你想要的东西♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ Then drop on the deck
.and flop like a fish ♪
♪ 然后落在甲板上
.然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants♪
♪ !海绵宝宝♪
♪ ?Ready
!SpongeBob SquarePants ♪
♪ 准备好了
！海绵宝宝♪
♪ !SpongeBob SquarePants
♪ !海绵宝宝
[laughs heartily ]
[尽情地笑]
Captioning sponsored by THE]
[U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION[ plays airy tune
字幕由 THE 赞助]
[美国教育部[演奏轻快的曲子
[and NICKELODEON
[和尼克罗迪恩
:SANDY
...You know, SpongeBob
:桑迪
...你知道，海绵宝宝
sometimes it's nice
to hang up my hang glider
有时很好
挂起我的悬挂式滑翔机
and just watch the clouds
.roll by
只看云彩
.滚过
.Yep. And just relax
。是的。放松一下
...Yeah
...是的
.relax
。放松
!Ooh! Ooh! Ooh
You know what that
?cloud looks like
！哦！哦！噢
你知道那是什么
？云看起来像
?What
？什么
.A flower
.一朵花
,They all look like flowers
.SpongeBob... all the time
,它们看起来都像花
.海绵宝宝...一直
.They sure do
.他们确实这样做
You know, normally
I'd offer to race you
你知道，通常情况下
我愿意和你比赛
to the top
of Coral Cliffs
到顶部
珊瑚悬崖
but I don't
want to miss out
但我不
想要错过
on a second of this
.beautiful beauty
在这一秒
.美丽的美丽
.Me either
。我也是
Who wants to get
?all dirty anyway
谁想得到
？反正都很脏
.Yeah... and sweaty
.是的...还有汗
Besides, I think we know
.who'd get to the top first
此外，我想我们知道
.谁会先到达顶峰
.Yeah
。是的
[both laugh ]
[两人都笑了]
:BOTH
.Me
：两者
.我
.That's funny, Sandy
.这很有趣，桑迪
It sounded
like you said
听起来
就像你说的
you could beat me
.in a climbing contest
你可以打败我
.在攀岩比赛中
!'Course I can
！'当然可以
!I'm a squirrel
！我是一只松鼠
!See
！看
I thought that meant
.you were nuts
我以为这意味着
.你疯了
Nope. It means I'm
!a natural born climber
没有。这意味着我是
！天生的登山者
I'm from the surface world
我来自地表世界
and nothing prepares you
for climbing
没有什么能让你做好准备
用于攀登
like growing up
.on good old dry land
就像长大一样
.在古老的干燥土地上
[laughs ]
[笑]
!Land-shmand
!土地施曼德
It's all about
.finger strength, baby
这都是关于
.手指力量，宝贝
And if there's anything
we've got plenty of down here
如果有什么的话
我们这里有很多
.it's finger strength
.这是手指的力量
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
,What do you say to that
?Miss Mittens
,你对此有何看法
?连指手套小姐
I say I'm already
!halfway there
我说我已经
！到了一半
!Aah
！啊啊
[panting ]
[气喘吁吁]
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
!No fair, Sandy
！不公平，桑迪
!You got a head start
！你已经领先了
!Sorry, SpongeBob
！对不起，海绵宝宝
That's the way
!the coral crumbles
就是这样
！珊瑚碎裂
!Hey
！嘿
!Ohh
！哦哦
!You did that on purpose
！你是故意的
.Yeah, but this is a accident
.是的，但这是一个意外
!Aah
！啊啊
Too bad you forgot
.your umbrella
可惜你忘记了
.你的伞
♪ !...I didn't
♪ ！...我没有
[laughing ]
[笑]
Well, it's about time
.you showed up
嗯，是时候了
.你出现了
...But you were
...I saw you... I
...但你是
...我看到你了...我
!I want a rematch
！我想要重赛
First one to the Krusty Krab
.is the winner
第一个去蟹堡
.是赢家
Ain't no way
a sea critter
没办法
一种海洋生物
can run faster
!than a land critter
可以跑得更快
！比陆地动物
.I can underwater
.我可以在水下
...I'm
...我是
!hydrodynamically designed
!流体动力学设计
Think you can win
a fair race
认为你能赢
公平的比赛
in that clunky
?tin tube
在那个笨重的
?锡管
Why don't you ask
?my be-hind
你为什么不问
？我的落后
...That is
.if you can catch it
...那就是
.如果你能抓住它
,What do you say to that
?Hydropants
,你对此有何看法
?吸水裤
I say, I'm already
...halfway there
我说我已经
...一半的地方
...halfway there
!Hey
！嘿
[laughing ]
[笑]
!Thanks for the face lift
！谢谢你的整容手术
[laughing ]
[笑]
You see, I told you
...you didn't have a
你看，我告诉过你
...你没有
!There you are
！你来了
Ain't that just
like a land creature
这不只是
像陆地生物一样
...to keep a sea creature
...饲养海洋生物
!waiting...
！等待...
[laughing ]
[笑]
I thought y'all
!wanted a rematch
我以为你们都
！想要重赛
I did! And I took
!a head start like you did
我做到了！我拿了
!像你一样领先
I was just funnin'
!with ya that time
我只是开玩笑
！那时和你一起
But I guess all y'all underwater
!don't have to play fair
但我猜你们都在水下
！不必公平竞争
,I guess we don't
!air breather
，我想我们没有
!空气呼吸器
!Water sucker
！吸水器
!Tree climber
！爬树者
.Gulf streamer
.海湾飘带
!Kite flier
！放风筝
!Chum chewer
！密友咀嚼者
[gasps ]
[喘气]
...Take that back, you
.not... wet... person
……收回那句话吧，你
.不...湿...人
Aha! You can't
even come up
!with another name
啊哈！你不能
甚至出现
!用另一个名字
!That proves it
！这证明了这一点
?Proves what
?证明了什么
That land critters are
.better than sea critters
陆地动物是
?Better at what
？擅长什么
,Oh, durn near everything
.I guess
，哦，该死的一切
.我猜
Cattle ropin and pie eatin'
and wood choppin'
牛绳和馅饼吃'
和砍柴'
.and flyin'
.然后飞翔
What's she
?blabbering about
她是什么
？闲聊
She says land creatures
.are best
她说陆地生物
.是最好的
Only 'cause
.it's true
只是因为
.这是真的
We're best at horseridin'
.and fur stylin' and rowin'
我们最擅长骑马
.还有皮草造型和划船
Y'all got us licked in swimmin'
你们让我们在游泳时被舔了
but we got corn shuckin'
但我们有玉米剥壳
and hay bailin'
and barn raisin'
和干草 bailin'
和谷仓葡萄干
!and... fishin'
！还有……钓鱼
[all gasp ]
[全都喘气]
And name callin'
.fer sure
并呼唤名字
.确定
!And drowning
!Don't forget drowning
！还有溺水
！别忘了溺水
[laughs ]
[笑]
!Good one, Squidward
!Whoo
！好样的，章鱼哥
！呼
,Not on your life
.sport
,不影响你的生活
.运动
.I'll admit
.我承认
You've got some pretty
.good moves, for a squirrel
你有一些漂亮的
.对于松鼠来说，动作不错
[...all laughing ]
[……全都笑了]
[laughter stops ]
[笑声停止]
But you're still
.just a land creature
但你还是
.只是一个陆地生物
Squirrels can do
!anything they want to
松鼠可以做
！他们想要的任何东西
I bet you can't eat a Krabby
.Double Deluxe in one bite
我打赌你不能吃蟹
.一口豪华双人床
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
...Ah
...啊
!Give me that
！给我那个
They don't call me Cheeks
.for nothin'
他们不叫我脸颊
.无缘无故
[all laugh ]
[全场大笑]
.Well, that's just one thing
.好吧，这只是一件事
?Can you do this
？你能做到吗
Everyone in my family
!can do that
我家里的每个人
！可以做到这一点
...Uh... uh
...呃...呃
?How about this, huh
？这个怎么样？
?Can you reproduce by budding
？可以通过出芽繁殖吗
?Can ya
？可以吗？
!No
！不
Most importantly
最重要的是
?can you do this
？你能做到吗
[gasping ]
[喘气]
Well, what would I want to do
嗯，我想做什么
any of that dumb stuff
?for anyway
任何愚蠢的东西
？无论如何
--Admit it, Sandy
——承认吧，桑迪
you can't do anything
!us sea creatures can do
你什么也做不了
！我们的海洋生物可以做到
In fact, if it wasn't
for that suit
事实上，如果不是
为了那套西装
you couldn't even
!live down here
你甚至不能
！住在这里
[laughing ]
[笑]
...Well, you don't
...好吧，你不
[laughing ]
[笑]
...I don't need to
...我不需要
[laughing ]
[笑]
...Grr
...咕噜
!I'll show y'all
！我会告诉你们
!I don't need this suit
！我不需要这套衣服
!Yah
！啊啊
[all gasp ]
[全都喘气]
And I don't need
!this helmet neither
而我不需要
！这个头盔也没有
!Neptune preserve her
！海王星保护她
How long can she
?stay like that
她还能坚持多久
？保持这样
.I don't know
。我不知道
?Sandy's a girl
？桑迪是个女孩
.Wow, Sandy
.哇，桑迪
.You sure proved us wrong
.你确实证明我们错了
I guess land creatures
.are better
我猜是陆地生物
.更好
At least, until they need
...to breathe
至少，直到他们需要
...呼吸
[all chuckle ]
[全场笑声]
.Yep, won't be long now
.是的，不会太久了
[groans ]
[呻吟]
?Feeling lightheaded yet
？还感觉头晕
:[groans ]
.Uh-uh
：[呻吟]
.呃呃
?Remember this
？记住这个
[breathing deeply ]
[深呼吸]
:KRABS
!It's free
:蟹蟹
！它是免费的
[breathing deeply ]
[深呼吸]
[...groaning ]
[...呻吟]
[gasps, gurgles ]
[喘气，咯咯声]
[gasping ]
[喘气]
[others laughing ]
[其他人笑]
!Stop laughin' at me
！别笑我了
!I knew it
！我就知道
There was no way
"some "airhead
没有办法
“一些”空头
was going to win anything
!against a water breather
会赢得任何东西
!对抗水呼吸者
...Airhead
...空头
[laughs ]
[笑]
?Huh
？哈
:ALL
!...Sea creatures rule
:全部
！...海洋生物统治
!Water! Water! Water
！水！水！水
,All right
.all right
,好吧
.好吧
You had your
.little laugh
你有你的
.小笑
But now
!it's my turn
但现在
！轮到我了
Y'all think you're
?such hot stuff, don't ya
你们都认为你是
？这么热的东西，不是吗？
Swimmin' around with
!your fancy gills 'n such
和一起游泳
！你那漂亮的鳃
But none of you wet heads
.would last a minute on my turf
但你们谁都湿了头
.在我的地盘上会持续一分钟
!Dry land
！旱地
Do we have to wear
?pickle jars
我们必须穿吗
?泡菜罐
[all laugh ]
[全场大笑]
Nope, nothin' but the clothes
!on your backs
不，除了衣服什么都没有
！在你的背上
?One minute
!No problem... landy
?一分钟
！没问题...兰迪
[all laugh ]
[全场大笑]
[continue laughing ]
[继续笑]
?Well, so are you going or not
？那么，你去还是不去
:ALL
...Uh... well... we... uh
:全部
...呃...好吧...我们...呃
...Actually... uh
...you know... uh
……其实……呃
...你知道...呃
...We can't... uh
...because
...我们不能...呃
...因为
We're... late
...for... um
我们……迟到了
...为了...嗯
!Our fitting
！我们的配件
Oh, you mean
?for your chicken costumes
哦，你的意思是
？为你的小鸡服装
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
!Hey... we are not chicken
！嘿...我们不是鸡
!gasps] My popcorn ]
!喘气]我的爆米花]
,Yeah, we're not chicken
.we'll do it
是的，我们不是鸡
.我们会做的
!There! Mission accomplished
！那里！任务完成
Look, unless you can stay above
water for one measly minute
看，除非你能留在上面
水一分钟
you forfeit the contest
你放弃比赛
and prove that land creatures
!are better than sea creatures
并证明陆地生物
！比海洋生物更好
.No way, San-day
.没门，桑迪
We can take on
.your challenge
我们可以承担
.你的挑战
:OTHERS
!Yeah
:其他
！是啊
We're not afraid of
.your dumb old land
我们不怕
.你那愚蠢的老土地
:OTHERS
!Yeah
:其他
！是啊
!We're sea creatures
！我们是海洋生物
:ALL
!Yeah
:全部
！是啊
.Okay
。好的
.Well, this is it
.嗯，就是这样
!Wait, boy
！等等，男孩
.Make it last
.让它持续下去
[gulping ]
[吞咽]
.Thanks, Mr. Krabs
.谢谢蟹老板
...Okay
...好的
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
!Here I go
！我来了
[gasping ]
[喘气]
[breathing more easily ]
[呼吸更顺畅]
!Hey... this isn't so bad
！嘿...这还不错
!We can do this
！我们可以做到这一点
!Hey, Patrick, come on up
！嘿，帕特里克，来吧
!The air is fine
！空气很好
I'm gonna do it quick
.and get it over with
我会快点做
.然后结束它
!...Cannonball
！...炮弹
!Hey, I lost my trunks
！嘿，我的内裤丢了
!Hi, SpongeBob
！嗨，海绵宝宝
!All right, Pat
!You made it
！好吧，帕特
！你做到了
!Mr. Krabs
！先生。蟹蟹
,Come on up
!Mr. Krabs
,上来吧
！先生。蟹蟹
,All ashore that's goin' ashore
!Mr. Squidward
,所有即将上岸的人都上岸了
！先生。章鱼哥
!Land... ho
！陆地...嗬
,Lookin' good
!Mr. Krabs
,看起来不错
！先生。蟹蟹
!Yeah, whoo-hoo
！是的，呼呼
,Come on
!Squidward
,来吧
！章鱼哥
You're missing
.all the dry
你失踪了
.所有的干燥
,Come on
!Squidward
,来吧
！章鱼哥
:ALL
!Squidward! Squidward
:全部
！章鱼哥！章鱼哥
...Well, I'll do it
.but I won't like it
……嗯，我会做的
.但我不会喜欢它
...Squidward! Squidward! Squid
……章鱼哥！章鱼哥！乌贼
?What
？什么
!Well, here we are
！好吧，我们到了
:SQUIDWARD
!This is pretty easy
：章鱼哥
！这很简单
:PATRICK
I may keep a second rock
!up here
：帕特里克
我可能会保留第二块石头
！在这里
:KRABS
,Once you get your land legs
!it's not so bad
:蟹蟹
,一旦你有了陆地腿
！还不错
We're the masters
我们是主人
!of land and sea
!陆地和海洋
!Hey, it's a local. Hi
！嘿，这是当地人。你好
!We're from underwater
！我们来自水下
?Do you know Sandy Cheeks
？你认识桑迪·奇克斯吗
...Three, two, one
...三、二、一
!Well, tan my fur
！好吧，晒黑我的毛皮
!They made it
！他们做到了
!Better go congratulate them
！最好去祝贺他们
?SpongeBob
?海绵宝宝
?Patrick
？帕特里克
Hmm, where did those
?critters get to
嗯，那些在哪里
？小动物到达
[all screaming ]
[全都尖叫]
!Holy Guacamole
！神圣鳄梨酱
,You can't eat my friends
!you rats with wings
,你不能吃我的朋友
！你们这些长着翅膀的老鼠
!Hi-yah
！嗨呀
[grunting and karate-yelling ]
[咕哝和空手道叫喊]
[splash ]
[飞溅]
Uh, thanks for
.saving us, Sandy
呃，谢谢
.拯救我们，桑迪
You know everyone's
.best at something
你知道每个人的
.最擅长某事
But no one's best
.at everything
但没有人是最好的
.在一切方面
Sorry I made you take off
.your helmet, Sandy
抱歉我让你起飞了
.你的头盔，桑迪
Sorry I made you go up
.on dry land, SpongeBob
抱歉我让你上去
.在干燥的土地上，海绵宝宝
Three cheers for feeling
!sorry for ourselves
为感觉干杯三声
！对不起我们自己
...Hip-hip
...嘻哈
:ALL
!Hooray
:全部
！万岁
...Hip-hip
...嘻哈
:ALL
!Hooray
:全部
！万岁
...Hip-hip
...嘻哈
:BOTH
...Hooray
：两者
...万岁
:NARRATOR
Ah... the Bikini Bottom Zoo
.is having its annual free day
:旁白
啊……比基尼动物园
.正在迎来一年一度的免费日
...Free balloons
...免费气球
...free drinks
...免费饮料
?free light bulbs
?免费灯泡
!Aha
！啊哈
!Top 'o the mornin', boys
！早上好，孩子们
[laughs nervously ]
[紧张地笑]
.Whew! Next stop.. gift shop
.哇！下一站..礼品店
--There it is
.Oyster Stadium
——就在这儿
.牡蛎体育场
Not only do they have
他们不仅有
the largest oyster
held in captivity
最大的牡蛎
被囚禁
.it also does tricks
.它也有技巧
:[dramatic voice ]
He spits a giant pearl
：[戏剧性的声音]
他吐出一颗巨大的珍珠
100 feet in the air
100 英尺空中
!like a cannon ball
！像炮弹一样
Why are we hanging around
!?watching a cheap imitation
我们为何徘徊
！？看着廉价的仿制品
!Let's get over there
！我们去那里吧
:BOTH
This is the greatest day
!of our lives
：两者
这是最伟大的一天
！我们的生活
[...snoring and gurgling ]
[...打鼾和咯咯声]
This is the greatest
?day of our lives
这是最伟大的
？我们生命中的一天
.Boring
。无聊的
,You're right, Patrick
...we came to see
，你是对的，帕特里克
...我们来看
!pearls 100 feet in the air
?Right
!珍珠100英尺高空
？对吧
.I'll try my oyster call
.我会尝试我的牡蛎叫声
[...gibbering and trilling ]
[...胡言乱语和颤音]
.Well, I'm outta here
.好吧，我要离开这里了
,Thanks for nothin'
.SpongeBob
，谢谢什么
.海绵宝宝
[snoring and gurgling ]
[打鼾和咕噜声]
,Come on, come on
!wake up already
,来吧,来吧
！已经醒来了
[grunts ]
[咕哝]
[gurgling ]
[咕噜声]
!I think it's working
！我认为它正在发挥作用
[gurgling ]
[咕噜声]
[grunting anxiously ]
[焦急地咕哝]
!Hey, Patrick, it's waking up
！嘿，帕特里克，它醒了
?Oh boy, did I miss it
？天哪，我错过了吗
No, the show's
...about to begin
不，节目的
...即将开始
[whimpering ]
[呜咽]
[...wailing loudly ]
[……大声哀嚎]
What's wrong
?with Clamu
怎么了
？与克拉穆
[...wailing ]
[...哀号]
,Easy, girl, it's me
?Joe, remember
，简单点，女孩，是我
？乔，记住
[snarling ]
[咆哮]
[screaming ]
[尖叫]
!Now, this is a show
！现在，这是一场表演
:[.MAN [ on p.a
.Attention, zoo patrons
:[.MAN [ 于 p.a
.动物园的顾客们请注意
Clamu The Giant Oyster
!is on an emotional rampage
巨型牡蛎克拉姆
！情绪激动
Please scream and
.run around in circles
请尖叫并
.绕圈子
[all scream ]
[全场尖叫]
.Thanks for coming
.感谢您的光临
[...snarling and wailing ]
[...咆哮和哀号]
You boys better get
!out of this area, pronto
你们男孩们最好得到
！马上离开这个区域
There's nothing
more dangerous
什么都没有
更危险
than an emotionally
.disturbed oyster
而非情感上的
.受干扰的牡蛎
You didn't do anything
你什么也没做
that might have caused
?this tragedy, did you
这可能导致
？这场悲剧，你
...Uh
...呃
No way! Only a jerk
.would upset a gentle giant
决不！只是一个混蛋
.会让一个温柔的巨人心烦意乱
?Right, SpongeBob
？对吧，海绵宝宝
.Right
。正确的
[...wailing ]
[...哀号]
:PATRICK
Man, if I ever see
the guy who upset Clamu
：帕特里克
伙计，如果我见过
那个让克拉穆心烦意乱的人
I'd have a few choice words
...for him, like
我有几个选择的话
……对他来说，就像
..."you"... and... "are"
"!and... "a jerk
...“你”...和...“是”
“！还有……”一个混蛋
Are you sure you didn't see
?anything suspicious
你确定你没看到吗
?有任何可疑之处
,I already said I didn't
!Patrick, sheesh
,我已经说了我没有
！帕特里克，谢什
Hey, lets investigate
this crime
嘿，让我们调查一下
这个罪行
and catch the lowlife
.who's responsible
抓住低贱的人
.谁负责
!Give it a rest, Patrick
！休息一下，帕特里克
There's no crime
to investigate
没有犯罪
调查
!Now go home
！现在回家吧
...Stupid Patrick
!I didn't do anything wrong
...愚蠢的帕特里克
！我没有做错任何事
Aw, what am I getting
?so worked up about
噢，我得到了什么
？所以很兴奋
I'm sure that by tomorrow
我确信到明天
this whole ugly mess
will be a funny memory
[chuckles ]
这整个丑陋的混乱
将是一个有趣的回忆
[笑声]
Our top story
:tonight
我们的头条新闻
：今晚
giant oyster has
!its feelings hurt
巨型牡蛎有
！它的感情受到伤害
The only clue
that could be found
唯一的线索
可以找到的
!was this lone peanut
！就是这个孤独的花生吗？
,And as you can hear
the oyster continues
,正如你所听到的
牡蛎继续
to emit its horrible cry
发出可怕的叫声
A cry so powerful, it can
be heard around the world
哭声如此有力，它可以
被世界各地听到
A cry that not only
breaks the sound barrier
哭声不仅
打破音障
it breaks the hearts
!of our citizens
它伤透了心
！我们的公民
,What kind of cruel
careless, evil person
，这是何等的残忍
粗心、邪恶的人
would deliberately upset one of
?Neptune's most gentle creatures
会故意扰乱其中之一
?海王星最温柔的生物
[meows ]
[喵]
!Aah
！啊啊
No, Gary! How would I know
?anything about the oyster
不，加里！我怎么知道
?关于牡蛎的任何事情
[meows ]
[喵]
Defensive? I'm not
!being defensive
防守？我不是
！处于防御状态
,Barnacles! What is this
?20 questions or something
，藤壶！这是什么
?20 个问题什么的
[...Clamu wailing ]
[...克拉穆哀嚎]
This is getting
.a little out of hand
这正在得到
.有点失控
.All I did was throw a peanut
.我所做的只是扔了一颗花生
I didn't mean
!to make the oyster cry
我不是这个意思
！让牡蛎哭泣
I just wanted to see it
!perform spectacular stunts
我只是想看看
!表演精彩的特技
!Aw, everyone's going to hate me
！噢，每个人都会恨我的
.I, I need some advice
.我，我需要一些建议
...Now, let's see now
...现在，让我们看看
who could never hate me
?no matter what I do
谁永远不会恨我
？无论我做什么
!Squidward
！章鱼哥
!Squidward! Oh Squidward
！章鱼哥！哦章鱼哥
SpongeBob! Do you have
?to knock so loudly
海绵宝宝！你有吗
？敲得那么大声
!Sorry, neighbor
！对不起，邻居
Oh... that
overgrown clam
哦...那个
长满的蛤
is giving me
!a headache
正在给我
！头疼
I can't even take
my afternoon
!beauty nap
我什至无法接受
我的下午
！美容午睡
[laughs nervously ]
[紧张地笑]
Funny thing you should
mention that old oyster
有趣的事情你应该
提到那只老牡蛎
...Because I... uh
...was kind wondering, um
...因为我...呃
...有点想知道，嗯
Let's say I know this guy
假设我认识这个人
who may have something
.to do with the oyster
谁可能有东西
.与牡蛎有关
!?You know the guy who did it
！？你认识做这事的人
[gulps ]
[咽口水]
!Oh, this is great
！哦，这太棒了
You and I can go
!turn him in
你和我可以走
！把他交出来
,And then I'll get so much sleep
!I'll be gorgeous
，然后我就会睡很多觉
！我会很漂亮
...Um, actually, I
.I'm just talking hypothetically
……嗯，其实我
.我只是假设性地说
You don't
?know who did it
你不
？知道是谁干的
!Well, um, I, uh, no
！嗯，嗯，我，呃，不
?Squidward
?章鱼哥
!Gotcha
！明白了
!Aah
！啊啊
Where were you
?on the day of today
你在哪里
？今天这一天
Don't play games
!with me, mister
不要玩游戏
！跟我一起，先生
,Hey, Patrick
?what are you doing
，嘿，帕特里克
?你在做什么
!Oh hi, SpongeBob
！哦嗨，海绵宝宝
I'm just continuing
my investigation
我只是继续
我的调查
!of the great Clamu Caper
!伟大的克拉姆·卡佩尔
Um... have you found out
?anything
嗯……你发现了吗
？任何东西
!Yes
！是的
.No, wait... um... no
.不，等等...嗯...不
But this grain of sand
looks pretty suspicious
但这粒沙
看起来很可疑
!and so does this rock
！这块岩石也是如此
And I've got a few questions
!for this little piece of grass
我有几个问题
！为了这一小片草
,Don't worry, SpongeBob
!Patrick's on the case
，别担心，海绵宝宝
！帕特里克正在处理此案
The truth will be
!revealed
真相将是
！揭晓
,I'd better go see Sandy
!she'll know what to do
,我最好去见桑迪
！她会知道该怎么做
!Clamu wailing...]Ohh, I can't stand it anymore ]
！Clamu 哀号...]哦，我再也受不了了]
,That poor
!poor critter
,那个可怜的
！可怜的小动物
What kind of
inconsiderate person
什么样的
不体贴的人
would upset
?such a gentle creature
会心烦意乱
？如此温柔的生物
Uh, that's kind of what I
...wanted to talk to you about
呃，这就是我的情况
...想和你谈谈
Why, when I find out who caused
that oyster so much pain
为什么，当我发现是谁造成的
那个牡蛎太痛苦了
!No more jiggery pokery
！不再有摇摇欲坠的扑克游戏
[grunting ]
[咕噜声]
Now, what was it you wanted
?to talk about, SpongeBob
现在，你想要什么
？谈谈，海绵宝宝
[gibbering ]
[胡言乱语]
Hey, SpongeBob, how come
?you're all twitchy like that
嘿，海绵宝宝，怎么会这样
？你们都像那样抽搐
?Twitchy? Twitchy
?Who's twitchy
？抽搐？抽搐
?谁在抽搐
!I'm not twitchy
！我没有抽搐
,Sorry, Sandy
...I have to um, um
，对不起，桑迪
...我必须嗯，嗯
.go get my hair cut
.去剪头发吧
...SpongeBob doesn't have hair
...海绵宝宝没有头发
?or does he
？还是他
[panting and whimpering ]
[喘息和呜咽]
!Hey, SpongeBob
！嘿，海绵宝宝
!This is it
！就是这样
All of the clues
!are coming together
所有的线索
！在一起了
I followed these footprints
right to this exact spot
我跟随这些脚印
就到这个地方
and then, right
...where you're standing
然后，对
……你站的地方
I found this bag
!of peanuts! Ha
我找到了这个包
！花生！哈
Oh, I'm so close
to solving this crime
哦，我是如此接近
来解决这个犯罪问题
!I can almost taste it
！我几乎可以尝到它的味道
...Mmm
...嗯
Boy, crime-fighting
sure makes me hungry
男孩，打击犯罪
肯定让我饿了
and this
yellow popsicle
!hits the spot
还有这个
黄色冰棒
！恰到好处
Okay, uh, good luck
with all that, Patrick
好吧，祝你好运
尽管如此，帕特里克
...and, uh
!I'll see you later
...还有，呃
！稍后见
[chattering and whimpering ]
[喋喋不休和呜咽]
:MAN
!Open up
!This is the police
:曼
！打开
！这是警察
!Uh, uh, just a second
！呃，呃，请等一下
?Are you SpongeBob SquarePants
?你是海绵宝宝吗
?Y-y-yes
？是-是-是的
Put those eyeballs
.back in your head, son
把那些眼球
.回到你的脑海里，儿子
We've got a few
.questions for you
我们有几个
.向你提问
Were you at the zoo
你在动物园吗
on the day of the
?oyster incident
当天
？牡蛎事件
!Um, um, um, yes
！嗯，嗯，嗯，是的
Did you, or did you not
take part
你有没有
参加
in various activities
?of zoo-time merriment
在各种活动中
?动物园里的欢乐时光
...Yes
...是的
...And are you familiar with
?this peanut
...你熟悉吗
?这个花生
!Yes
！是的
...Just one more question
...还有一个问题
Is it true that you were
at the oyster's lair
你是真的吗
在牡蛎的巢穴
?with a Mr. Patrick Star
？与帕特里克·明星先生
:[crying ]
!Yes! Yes! It's true
：[哭]
！是的！是的！这是真的
!It's all true
！这都是真的
,The merriment
...the peanut
,欢乐
...花生
!the Patrick
！帕特里克
!That's all we need to know, son
！这就是我们需要知道的一切，儿子
!Let's book him
！我们来预订他吧
!Wow, you guys are good
！哇，你们真好
I'm the last person
I would have suspected
我是最后一个人
我本来会怀疑
but I was looking for me
!all the time
但我一直在寻找我
！一直
!It's the perfect crime
！这是一次完美的犯罪
Yeah, yeah, tell it
!to the judge, pinky
是啊是啊，快说吧
！给法官，小指
Oh no! Patrick's too sensitive
!for the big house
哦不！帕特里克太敏感了
！为了大房子
[siren wailing ]
[警笛哀嚎]
!Wait, stop
！等等，停下来
!I'm the one you want
！我就是你想要的人
!I am the criminal
！我是罪犯
[...crowd yelling and booing ]
[...人群大喊大叫和嘘声]
Hey, everybody, let's
throw peanuts at him
嘿，大家，让我们
向他扔花生
!and see how he likes it
！看看他有多喜欢
[crowd yelling ]
[人群喊叫]
!I get what I deserve
！我得到了我应得的
[gulping ]
[吞咽]
!Ouch
！哎哟
[crowd booing ]
[人群起哄]
!Wait
！等待
!Hold your peanuts
！抱住你的花生
!Patrick Star is innocent
！帕特里克·斯塔是无辜的
I have come here
!to reveal the truth
我来过这里
!揭露真相
They say
that truth and honesty
他们说
真理和诚实
will be rewarded
!with trust and forgiveness
将得到奖励
！带着信任和宽恕
humming ]
[...dramatic theme
嗡嗡声]
[...戏剧性的主题
I'm here to lay my cards
on the table
我是来打牌的
在桌子上
to trim the branches
of deception from
the tree of life
修剪树枝
的欺骗来自
生命之树
to shave away the unkempt
sideburns from the face
...of truth! I
刮掉蓬头垢面的
脸上的鬓角
...真理！我
Hey! Just get on
!with it
嘿！上车吧
！用它
I am the one
.who threw the peanut
我就是那个
.谁扔了花生
I know now that what
...I have done is wrong
我现在知道那是什么
...我所做的是错误的
,and so I say, I am sorry
!giant performing oyster
，所以我说，对不起
！巨大的表演牡蛎
.I am sorry, Patrick
.对不起，帕特里克
,I am sorry
citizens of Bikini Bottom
,对不起
比基尼堡公民
[Patrick stops humming ]
[帕特里克停止哼唱]
Hey! Let's
throw peanuts
!at both of 'em
嘿！让我们
扔花生
！在他们两个
[crowd yelling ]
[人群喊叫]
.Wait! Here's the real criminal
。等待！这才是真正的罪犯
?Uh... top of the morning
？呃...早上起来
!Mr. Krabs
！先生。蟹蟹
[crowd gasps ]
[人群倒吸一口凉气]
!I knew it
！我就知道
Mr. Krabs stole
a very important item
蟹老板偷了
一个非常重要的项目
!from the oyster
!来自牡蛎
...Behold
...看哪
[crowd groans in disgust ]
[人群厌恶地呻吟]
...Wait a minute
...等一下
!Behold
！看哪
!The oyster's pearl
！牡蛎的珍珠
[crowd gasps ]
[人群倒吸一口凉气]
.Here you go, girl
.给你，女孩
[sniffing ]
[嗅嗅]
[crowd cheering ]
[人群欢呼]
[crowd gasps ]
[人群倒吸一口凉气]
:[gurgling ]
!Mama! Mama
：[咕噜声]
！妈妈！妈妈
!Mother of pearl
!珍珠母贝
!The oyster's a mother
！牡蛎是母亲
.And that pearl's no pearl
.那颗珍珠不是珍珠
!It's an egg
！这是一个鸡蛋
:[gurgling ]
!Mama! Mama
：[咕噜声]
！妈妈！妈妈
[gurgling ]
[咕噜声]
[both gurgling happily ]
[两人开心地咯咯笑]
:ALL
...Aw
:全部
...噢
!But it's... free day
！但今天是...自由活动日
[crowd yelling ]
[人群喊叫]
and NICKELODEON
和尼克国际儿童频道
Captioned byThe Caption Center
[WGBH Educational Foundation
字幕由字幕中心提供
[WGBH 教育基金会